A Finding Aid to the William Mills Ivins Papers, 1878-1964, in the Archives of American Art
Archives of American Art
William Mills Ivins papers
1878-1964
Archives of American Art
Ivins, William Mills, 1881-1961
AAA.ivinwill
Archival Resource Key
20.5 Linear feet
The papers, 1878-1964 (20.5 linear feet) of museum curator, director, and art scholar William Mills Ivins (1881-1961) consist of correspondence, writings, notes, photographs, and Ivins family papers. Ivins was Curator of Prints, 1916-1946, Assistant Director, 1933-1938, and Acting Director, 1938-1940 at the Metropolitan Museum of Art. The collection contains professional and personal correspondence with art historians, art dealers, museum curators, print and book collectors, and artists concerning the history of print making, book design and illustration, print collectors and collecting, exhibitions, and museum administration. Also found are Ivins' published and unpublished writings and lectures, and notes. The collection contains some Ivins' family papers including family correspondence, genealogies, and photographs.
Biographical Note
William Mills Ivins, Jr. (1881-1961), a lawyer, first became interested in collecting prints and illustrated books while an undergraduate at Harvard. He studied the history of printmaking through self-directed reading, by looking at prints in the major European libraries and museums, and tried his hand at many of the printmaking processes. While practicing law, he wrote articles and organized some small exhibitions of prints as early as 1908. In 1916, the Metropolitan Museum of Art appointed its first Curator of Prints to organize a Department of Prints and Drawings and to develop its small existing collection. Upon the recommendation of Paul J. Sachs who was unable to accept the position, Ivins was selected. He held the post until his retirement some thirty years later.
During his tenure as Curator of Prints, Ivins became one of the most highly-respected individuals in the profession. Under Ivins the collection grew in scope, size, and quality; he acquired materials by cultivating potential donors, and through systematic purchase of pieces not likely to come into the collection by bequest. The department's active exhibition schedule included some especially noteworthy shows, such as The Arts of the Book in 1924.
Ivins was knowledgeable and shared information by writing several books on prints and the history of printmaking, and by writing large numbers of articles for the educated layman. His articles often highlighted items in the permanent collection, and frequently appeared in the museum's Bulletin. He was interested in perspective, psychology of perception, aesthetics, mathematics and modern philosophy, and wrote on these topics, as well.
He was an accomplished speaker and was in much demand as a lecturer. Of particular note were his series on Illustrated Books of the Renaissance at the Morgan Library in 1936, and the 1950 Lowell Lectures (subsequently published under the title Prints and Visual Communication).
In addition to his curatorial duties, Ivins served as Assistant Director of the Metropolitan Museum of Art between 1933 and 1938, and was its Acting Director from 1938 until 1940. Francis Henry Taylor was appointed Director in 1940, and Ivins was named to the newly created post of Counselor; failure to attain the directorship was a bitter disappointment, which many attributed to his lack of tact and generally difficult disposition.
Ivins retired in 1946, and continued to write and publish until the mid-1950's. During this period he was awarded an honorary doctorate by Yale University (1946), made an honorary fellow of the Metropolitan Museum of Art (1946), named a fellow of the American Academy of Arts and Sciences (1950), and invited to deliver the annual lectures at the Lowell Institute (1950). He died at the age of eighty in 1961, after several years of declining health.
Ivins' private collection of prints and illustrated books, which he had continued to amass through the 1930's, was partially dispersed during his lifetime through gifts to the Metropolitan Museum and to a number of university and special libraries. The portion remaining in his estate was sold at auction by Parke Bernet between 1962 and 1964.
Missing Title
1881 born to William Mills Ivins and Emma Yard Ivins, Flatbush, N.Y.
1890-1893 attended King's School, Stamford, Conn.
1896 trip to South America with father
1897 graduation from St. Paul's School, Concord, N.H.
1901 graduation from Harvard (A.B.)
1901-1902 travelled in Europe with Paul Haviland, and studied economics at University of Munich
1902-1904 employed by The World's Work, writing articles on economic and artistic subjects
1907 graduation from Columbia School of Law
1907-1916 practiced law in New York City: Ivins, Wolff and Houget for New York Public Service Commission, 1907-1908; Strong and Cadwallader, 1908-1909; Cravath, Henderson, and der Gersdorff, 1909-1916
1908 arranged first exhibition of prints, Keppel & Co,
1910 marriage to Florence Wyman, an illustrator
1916 appointed first Curator of Prints, Metropolitan Museum of Art
c. 1927-1935 served on editorial board of Metropolitan Museum Studies
1933-1938 Assistant Director, Metropolitan Museum of Art
1937 Morgan Library Lectures
1938 Honorary Curator of Prints and Drawings, Morgan Library
1938-1940 Acting Director, Metropolitan Museum of Art (Note: Mr. Ivins continued to act as Curator of Prints during periods when he was assigned other major administrative responsibilities at the museum)
1940 Counselor, Metropolitan Museum of Art
1946 Honorary Fellow, Metropolitan Museum of Art; retirement from Metropolitan Museum of Art; Honorary Doctorate, Yale University
1950 Fellow, American Academy of Arts and Sciences; Lowell Lectures (published in 1953 under the title Prints and Visual Communication)
1961 death
1962-1964 Ivins Collection of Prints and Illustrated Books sold at auction by Parke Bernet
1977-1983 William M. Ivins, Jr. Papers donated to the Archives of American Art by his daughter, Barbara Ivins
Scope and Content Note
The papers, 1878-1964 (20.5 linear feet) of museum curator, director, and art scholar William Mills Ivins (1881-1961) consist of personal and professional correspondence, writings, notes, photographs, and Ivins family papers. Ivins was Curator of Prints, 1916-1946, Assistant Director, 1933-1938, and Acting Director, 1938-1940 at the Metropolitan Museum of Art. The collection contains professional and personal correspondence with art historians, art dealers, museum curators, print and book collectors, and artists concerning the history of print making, book design and illustration, print collectors and collecting, exhibitions, and museum administration. Correspondence files appear to be complete, and correspondence is of substantive content. Also found are Ivins' published and unpublished writings and lectures, and notes. Of particular interest are the letters from Bernard Berenson, Paul J. Sachs, and Theodore Sizer, each of whom corresponded with Ivins freqently over extended periods about both personal and professional and matters.
Ivins' family papers include family correspondence, genealogies, and photographs. The papers of Ivin's wife, illustrator Florence Wyman Ivins (1881-1948), and the correspondence of several other relatives, can be found here augmented by family photographs.
Arrangement
The collection has been arranged into 7 series. The contents and organization are noted in the individual series descriptions.
Missing Title
Series 1: Professional and Personal Papers, circa 1908-1961 (Boxes 1-8; 6.5 linear ft.)
Series 2: Writings, circa 1910-1960 (Boxes 8-12; 4.9 linear ft.)
Series 3: Publications, 1896-1958 (Boxes 13-14; 2.0 linear ft.)
Series 4: Miscellaneous, 1915, undated (Box 15; 1.0 linear ft.)
Series 5: Ivins Family Papers, 1878-1964, undated (Boxes 16-20; 4.5 linear ft.)
Series 6: Photographs, circa 1890-1940 (Boxes 20-21; 1.5 linear ft.)
Series 7: Oversized Material, 1897-1950 (1 OV folder)
Provenance
The William Mills Ivins, Jr., papers were donated to the Archives of American Art by his daughter, Barbara Ivins, in several installments between 1977 and 1983.
Restrictions on Access
Use of unmicrofilmed material in the holdings of the Archives of American Art requires an appointment and is limited to the Washington, D.C., facility.
Illustrators; Aesthetics; Art museums; Book collectors and collecting; Museum directors; Perspective; Designers; Museums -- Acquisitions; Art historians; Prints -- History; Etching -- History; Engraving -- History; Medicine and art -- History; Illustrated books -- History; Museum curators; Metropolitan Museum of Art (New York, N.Y.); Lay, Charles Downing, 1877-1956; Ivins, William Mills, 1851-1915; Sachs, Paul J. (Paul Joseph), 1878-1965; Ruzicka, Rudolph, 1883-; Rogers, Bruce, 1870-1957; Pierpont Morgan Library; Webster, Herman A. (Herman Armour), 1878-1970; Sizer, Theodore, 1892-1967; Simonson, Lee, 1888-; Sarton, George, 1884-1956; Winter, Carl, 1906 Jan. 10-; Wind, Edgar, 1900-; Käsebier, Gertrude, 1852-1934; Ames, Winslow; Arensberg, Walter, 1878-1954; Arms, John Taylor, 1887-1953; Berenson, Bernard, 1865-1959; Century Association (New York, N.Y.); Ivins, Emma Yard, 1857-1940; Ivins, Barbara; Ivins, Katherine; Ivins, Florence Wyman, 1881-1948; Greene, Belle da Costa, 1883-1950; Friedländer, Max J., 1867-1958; Holmes, Margaret Ivins, 1882-1954; Grolier Club; Constable, W. G. (William George), 1887-1976; Cockerell, Sydney Carlyle, Sir, 1867-1962; Frankfurter, Felix, 1882-1965; Dodgson, Campbell, 1867-1948; Burroughs, Bryson, 1869-1934; Boas, George, 1891-; Carrington, Fitz Roy, 1869-1954
- Professional and Personal Papers, circa 1908-1961; Series 1; Archival Resource Key; (Boxes 1-8; 6.5 linear ft.)
  Scope and Contents note
  This series contains the personal and professional correspondence of William M. Ivins, Jr., consisting mainly of letters addressed to Ivins, with copies of his replies amounting to about five percent of the total. Correspondence with relatives can be found with the Ivins Family Papers.
  Of particular interest are the letters of Bernard Berenson, Paul J. Sachs, and Theodore Sizer, each of whom correspondend with Ivins frequently over extended periods; their letters pertain to both professional and personal matters. Very few copies of Ivins' letters to them are contained in the collection; however, Ivins' letters to Sizer (approximately 110 items, dated 1926-1959) are in the collection of Yale University Library.
  Also included are letters of condolence upon the death of his wife, Florence Wyman Ivins, in 1948, and correspondence and receipts from print dealers and booksellers concerning purchases for Ivins' personal collection.
  Arrangement note
  This series is organized into three subseries:
  1.1: Correspondence, A-Z, circa 1908-1961
  1.2: Metropolitan Museum of Art, General Office Files and Correspondence, circa 1919-1947
  1.3: Correspondence With Publishers, 1932-1958
  - Correspondence, A-Z, circa 1908-1961; 1.1; Archival Resource Key
    The correspondence is arranged alphabetically, usually by the author's name rather than the institution or firm represented. There are a very small number of files titled by subject (e.g., "Woodbury, Conn. property") included in the alphabetical sequence. The correspondents listed below are represented by at least ten letters each, with a separate folder for each individual. All others are in general files for each letter of the alphabet, with selected correspondents noted.
    - Correspondence, A, Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 1-2)
      (including Elmer Adler)
    - Alford, Roberta Fansler, 1933-1959; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Ames, Adelbert, Jr., 1940-1947; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 4)
      (about physiology of vision and psychology of perception)
    - Ames, Winslow, 1947-1958; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 5)
      (about WMI writings, particularly Art and Geometry; family news; announcement of departure from Springfield Art Museum)
    - Arensberg, Walter, 1909-1930; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 6)
      (recommending Marcel Duchamp and Walter Pach as assistants in Print Department; symbolism in "The Melancholia"; WMI's reminiscences of Arensberg [classmate, Harvard, 1090], in response to a request from Fiske Kimball)
    - Arms, John Taylor, 1930-1948; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 7)
      (tribute on the occasion of WMI's retirement; invitations; letters about juries, Brooklyn Society of Etchers, and other organizations for printmakers)
    - Atcheson, Topeka & Santa Fe Railway, 1911; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence, B, Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 9-13)
      (includes Barr, Alfred Hamilton, 1937; Beal, Gifford. 1935)
    - Baerwald, Emil, 1917-1949; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 14)
      (about print collecting and recent sales; comments on WMI writings; Max Friedlander)
    - Barlow, T. D., 1927-1953; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 15)
      (about print collecting and books)
    - Benson, John, 1952-1956; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Berenson, Bernard and Nicky, 1925-1926; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Berenson, Bernard and Nicky, 1927-1928; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Berenson, Bernard and Nicky, 1929; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Berenson, Bernard and Nicky, 1930; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Berenson, Bernard and Nicky, 1931; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Berenson, Bernard and Nicky, 1932; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Berenson, Bernard and Nicky, 1933; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Berenson, Bernard and Nicky, 1934; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Berenson, Bernard and Nicky, 1935; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Berenson, Bernard and Nicky, 1936-1939; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Berenson, Bernard and Nicky, 1946-1947; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Berenson, Bernard and Nicky, 1948-1949; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Berenson, Bernard and Nicky, 1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Berenson, Bernard and Nicky, 1951; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Berenson, Bernard and Nicky, 1952; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Berenson, Bernard and Nicky, 1953; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Berenson, Bernard and Nicky, 1954; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Berenson, Bernard and Nicky, 1955; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Berenson, Bernard and Nicky, 1956; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Berenson, Bernard and Nicky, 1957-1961; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Boas, George, Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 37-40)
    - Born, Kay, 1956-1961; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 41-43)
    - Brooks, Van Wyck, and Gladys, 1951-1959; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - Burroughs, Alan, 1934-1957; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - Burroughs, Bryson, 1922-1934; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 46)
      (MMA news, including death of E. Robinson; family news; charicatures of Acting Director Reily and unknown)
    - Burroughs, Louise [Mrs. Bryson], 1948-1961; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 47)
    - Correspondence, C, Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 48-52)
      (includes: Clarke, Kenneth, 1929; Cleland, Thomas; Cortissoz, Royal, 1916-1935)
    - Carrington, FitzRoy, 1908-1955; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 1)
      (about print collecting; WMI writings for Print Collectors Quarterly Print Dept., Museum of Fine Arts, Boston; recent books about prints; ts of article by FC, "Some Designs by Florence Wyman Ivins")
    - Century Association, 1934-1949; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 2)
      (includes: Beal, Gifford; Tack, Augustus Vincent)
    - Champion, Librarie Ancienne, 1921-1927; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 3)
      (correspondence, receipts and invoices regarding purchases by WMI for personal collection)
    - Chase, Beulah Dimmick, and Julian, 1946-1958; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Cockerell, Sydney Carlyle, 1921-1956; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 5)
      (about WMI's writings; calligraphy; books and collecting; Fitzilliam Museum; news of mutual friends)
    - Cohn, Alfred E., and Aggie Lockwood (Mrs. Manus [daughter?]), 1920-1959; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 6-7)
      (about art; philosophy; opinions of recently published books; comments on WMI's writings, particularly Art and Geometry; news of mutual friends; reports on health of AEC; also included are WMI's letters to AEC, removed from AEC's files and sent to WMI by the Executor of the estate)
    - Constable, William George, 1932-1961; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 8-9)
      (about his own writings and speeches, and those of WMI; Bernard Berenson; collection of Museum of Fine Arts, Boston; travels; fakes)
    - Correspondence, D, Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 10-12)
      (includes: Davies, Arthur B. 1921; Dillyae, Blanche, 1908-1909; duBois, Guy Pene, undated; Duchamp, Marcel, 1926-1927)
    - Dana, John Cotton, 1917-1925; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 13)
      (about organization of the Newark Public Library, recordkeeping, and curatorial practices)
    - DeForest, Robert W., 1918-1930; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 14)
      (about WMI writins; MMA administrative matters; invitations)
    - Dodgson, Campbell, 1918-1943; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 15)
      (about Contemporary Art Society, Museum of Fine Arts, Boston; and Print Collectors Quarterly)
    - Correspondence, E, Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 16)
      (includes Easby, Dudley T, 1948-1958)
    - Elliott, Huger, and Elizabeth Shippen Green, 1927-1949; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Emmett, Burton, 1921-1929; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Erlich, Evelyn, 1948-1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Correspondence, F, Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 20-21)
    - Firuski, Maurice, 1953-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 22)
      (books offered and purchased for WMI collection at Housatonuc Bookshop, Salisbury, Conn.; some news of mutual friends)
    - Frankfurter, Felix, 1940-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 23)
      (about Bernard Berenson; news of mutual friends)
    - Frick Collection, 1939-1947; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 24)
      (about WMI lectures there)
    - Friedlander, Max J., 1927-1945; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Fulton, John E., 1947-1948; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 26)
      (about Vesalius)
    - Correspondence, G, Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 27-28)
      (includes: Gabo, Miriam [Mrs. Naum], and Nina [daughter], 1942-1953; Gallatin, A. E., 1943-1947)
    - Ginsberg, Jekuthiel, 1942-1953; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 29)
      (about WMI articles for Scripta Mathematica)
    - Greene, Belle da Costa, 1917-1947; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 30)
      (about mutual friends; Bernard Berenson see also: Grolier Club Morgan Library)
    - Grolier Club, 1916-1959; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 31-34)
      (arrangements for exhibitions and other club business; includes letters from Cassatt, Mary, 1919, 1924; Greene, Belle da Costa, 1921; Havemeyer, Mrs. H.O., 1919; Pennell, Joseph, 1918-1921; Woodbury, Charles H. C., 1921; Young, Mahonri. undated; miscellaneous printed matter, notes, drafts and catalog text)
    - Correspondence, H, Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 1-4)
      (includes: Haviland, Paul, 1908; Hind, Arthur M., 1920-1953; Hopkinson, Charles, 1946-1952)
    - Harvard Club, Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Harvard University, Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 6)
      (includes Class of 1901; general)
    - Hauser, Walter, 1946-1956; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 7)
      (about MMA staff)
    - Hofer, Philip, 1935-1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Howard, Ros, 1945-1948; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 9)
      (about Art and Geometry; psychology and physiology of perception; Bernard Berenson)
    - Howson, Roger, 1953-1956; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence, I, Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Iconophiles, 1926-1953; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence, J, Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 13)
      (includes: Janson, H. W)
    - Correspondence, K, Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 14-17)
      (includes: Kepple, Frederick 1911-1913)
    - Kelley, Nicholas, 1920-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Kent, Henry W., 1910-1948; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 19-20)
      (comments on writings and speeches of WMI; MMA administration)
    - Correspondence, L, Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 21-22)
      (includes: Lehmann-Haupt, Hellmut, 1930; Loewy, Raymond, 1934)
    - Lay, Charles Downing, 1926-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 23)
      (about C. Goodhue Memorial Exhibition; WMI's writings; calligraphy; news of mutual friends)
    - Lefferts, Helen Lambert, 1957-1958; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 24)
      (about Daumier exhibition)
    - Library of Congress, 1945-1946; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Lockwood, Will, and Louise, 1955-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Lowell Institute, 1949; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 27)
      (regarding Annual Lectures)
    - Correspondence, M, Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 28-33)
      (includes MacBride, Henry, 1929; Mielziner, Leo, and Ella F. 1917-1955)
    - McMahon, A. Philip, 1928-1947; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 34)
      (about own writings and those of WMI)
    - Malloch, Archibald, 1932-1953; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 35)
      (about Vesalian essays)
    - Mansfield, Howard, and Helen, 1917-1948; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 36)
      (comments on WMI's writings; exhibitions and acquisitions of MMA; biographical notes on HM)
    - Mather, Frank Jewett, 1921-1946; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 37)
      (lists of printmakers for his book; about WMI review of Gabriel book)
    - Mayor, A. Hyatt, and Virginia, 1940-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 38)
      (about MMA; writings of WMI)
    - Merriman, Daniel, 1947-1956; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 39)
      (about Davenport College, Yale University)
    - Moe, Henry Allen, 1938-1955; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 40)
      (about perspective and geometry; applicants for Guggenheim Fellowships)
    - Morgan, Junius Spencer, Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 41)
      (about his collection and new acquisitions)
    - Morgan Library, 1922-1958; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 42)
      (appointment of WMI as Honorary Curator of Prints and Drawings; acquisitions; invitations; see also: Greene, Belle da Costa)
    - Mosenthal & Sons Insurance, Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 43)
    - Morison, Stanley, 1925-1934; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 44)
      (about books and prints; printing; The Fleuron (journal of typography); news of mutual friends)
    - Munroe, Vernon, 1923-1957; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Munson, Ida, 1960-1961; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, N, Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 3-5)
    - Newlin, Alice, 1924; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence, O, Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Oppenheimer, Henry, 1919-1936; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Osborne, William Church, 1925-1946; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 9)